Sin-Tat Fan

Software Developer (MDes in Interaction Design, BSc in Computer Science)

Software Developer with 9+ years of experience in crafting elegant technology solutions with JavaScript. Obtained a Master's degree in Design with solid knowledge in UI/UX Design. Proven experience to collaborate in an agile and close-knit team with designers and other developers to build high quality products throughout development process. Eager to help companies engaging and professional products.

Skills

- Web Frontend: HTML, CSS, SCSS, Tailwind CSS, JavaScript, Webpack, React, Next.js, Vue, GraphQL
- Backend / API Development: Node.js, TypeScript, NestJS, Express, PHP, Laravel
- Database: (Relational) MySQL; (NoSQL) MongoDB
- Infrastructure: AWS, Azure, Firebase, DigitalOcean, MongoDB Atlas, Redis
- Others: Figma, Adobe XD, Flutter (Dart), OpenAPI, GitLab Runner, GitHub Actions

Professional Experience

Senior Software Engineer

Innovation Network & Design (Group) Limited, Jan 2021 - Present

- Developed and optimized a performant admin portal with React (JavaScript) to increase frontend loading speed by 4x and reduced 50% of data transfer cost.
- Planned and implemented an e-commerce system from scratch in microservice architecture with TypeScript, Node.js, MongoDB, AWS and Vue to handle over 1,000 concurrent requests with 70% infrastructure cost reduction.
- Collaborated with backend engineers to design RESTful API and write documentations with OpenAPI.
- Managed CI/CD workflows on GitLab Runner to test and deploy software.
- Supervised a development team of five to manage deliverables of web development projects, provide mentorship and code reviews to ensure quality of code, and discuss about technical decisions.

Research Fellow (3-month Contract)

The Hong Kong Polytechnic University, Oct 2022 - Dec 2022

- Communicated with the project leader to refine the requirements of an interactive survey system.
- Worked with UI/UX designers to create the UI/UX design, ensure the feasibility of technical implementation, and improve the usability.
- Developed an interactive frontend in SPA with **React** and a RESTful API backend with **Laravel** (**PHP**).
- Developed a CMS with Next.js (React) for managing questionnaires to reduce 40% time of creating new surveys.

Full Stack Software Engineer

Innovation Network & Design (Group) Limited, Aug 2017 - Dec 2020

- Collaborated with other engineers to bring modern tech stacks (**Webpack**, **Vue.js** and **Flutter**) to the company and increased 40% of positive comments from clients.
- Developed a reusable admin panel package with **Laravel** and **Vue.js** for internal use to eliminate repetitive work and reduce 20% of development time in new projects.
- Assisted the support team to troubleshoot and resolve problems based on users' feedback.

Web Developer

Innovation Network & Design (Group) Limited, May 2013 - Jul 2017

- Implemented web frontend in HTML, CSS and JavaScript in accordance with design specifications.
- Reviewed project requirements to develop web backend in PHP with Laravel.

Education

Master of Design (Interaction Design)

The Hong Kong Polytechnic University, 2021 - 2022, Graduated with Distinction

 Collaborated with designers in diverse backgrounds to apply Design Thinking approach to conduct user research and synthesize insights, build prototypes, such as UI/UX design wireframes, and acquire theories of human-computer interaction and user experience.

Bachelor of Science (Computer Science)

The Chinese University of Hong Kong, 2013 - 2017

Focused on Data Structure, Algorithm, Database Systems and Software Engineering.